RESUME

AKSHAY SUDHAKAR MORE

Mobile: +91 90280 62900 Email ID: akshaysmore@gmail.com

OVERVIEW

Total 10 years 2 months of experience in Building and Industrial Automation. Expertise in Data Center, Health Care, Educational & Commercial projects. Worked on various types of HVAC systems. Commissioned many air handling units, air-cooled & water-cooled chiller plants, hot water systems, unitary and miscellaneous systems. Currently working as lead estimator at Honeywell Pune Office and supporting Americas (US & Canada) projects.

WORK EXPERIENCE & JOB RESPONSIBILITIES

1. Pre-Sales & Estimation Support:

- Providing estimation support at various stages of a project's development ranging from concept budgets to 'for construction' cost.
- Analyzing MEP drawings, specifications, proposals, and other construction documents to prepare accurate bill of materials, labor estimates, subcon cost, risk register and firm cost.
- Interacting with the relevant stakeholders for the scope resolution/ clarifications.
- Developing tools to optimize estimation process cycle.

2. Hardware Engineering:

- Designing systems with desired behavior in control environments.
- Reviewing all types of engineering documents to show accurate information of each system on hardware drawings.
- Generating sequence of operation to ensure effective working of HVAC devices.
- Providing value engineering solutions & early warning indications of possible cost deviation or cost impacts on project.
- Taking necessary actions like change order request for additional work and raise an RFI.

Knowledge on tools:

- AutoCAD, ExACT, Microsoft Office Tools
- Schedules (System Architecture, VAV Box, Valve, Damper, AFMS & VFD)

3. Software Programing:

- Verifying proposed or designed control system sequence of operation.
- Developing complex programs for multiple systems as per sequence of operation.
- Generating test plan for operators and field engineering team.
- Developing point schedule & database for user interface.
- Developing supervisory level programming.

Knowledge on tools:

- ComfortPoint Open Studio R210, EBI Software
- Controller Configuration Tool (CCT), System Configuration Tool (SCT), NAE Point Schedule

4. Graphics Designing:

- Designing graphics for all types of HVAC systems.
- Adding required automation items to ensure real time operations are visible.
- Designing tree structure, navigations, tables, charts, and animations.
- Development of interactive User Interfaces to represent sequential flow of every device operation.

Knowledge on tools:

- HMI Web Display Builder, Quick Builder
- · Graphics Generation Tool, Visio Graphics,

5. Commissioning:

- Point to point checkouts of controls system and preparing test reports.
- Verifying sequence of operation of all HVAC units with different configuration.
- Troubleshooting of devices/system/equipments for expected operation.
- 3rd party system's integrations (BACnet MS/TP, BACnet IP, MODBUS etc.)

- Demonstrating systems to BMS operators and owners.
- Handling sub-contractors and ensuring safe working practices are set up and followed.

6. Project Coordination:

- Conduct project meetings with technical and non-technical team members.
- Keeping track of project schedule, completion of various tasks and change orders.
- Ensuring required materials are ordered & delivered on time.
- Based on complexity & cost of project, planning various tasks of project.
- Working on individual tasks within stipulated time frame without any deviation in quality.
- Managing resources by descend active stewardship.
- Achieving customer satisfaction by understanding their needs & providing supports.

ONSITE EXPERIENCE (FROM MAY 2015 TO DECEMBER 2017)

- Arkansas State University Jonesboro/Newport/Beebe (AR USA)
 -Job Responsibility: Estimation, HVAC System Design, Network Design, Configuration, Programming, Commissioning, Troubleshooting, Customer Demonstration.
- Baptist Memorial Hospital North Mississippi, Oxford (MS, USA)
 -Job Responsibility: HVAC System Design, Network Design, Configuration, Programming, Commissioning, Troubleshooting, Subcontractor Management.
- South Arkansas Community College El Dorado (AR, USA)
 -Job Responsibility: HVAC System Design, Network Design, Configuration, Programming,
 Commissioning, Troubleshooting, Subcontractor Management, Customer Demonstration.
- Middlesex County Vocational Technical School Edison (NJ, USA)
 -Job Responsibility: HVAC System Design, Network Design, Configuration, Programming, Commissioning, Troubleshooting, Subcontractor Management, Customer Demonstration.
- Middletown School District Middletown (NJ, USA)
 -Job Responsibility: Programming, Commissioning, Troubleshooting, Subcontractor Management, Customer Demonstration.
- Cognate Bio Services Memphis (TN, USA)
 -Job Responsibility: Programming, Commissioning, Troubleshooting, Subcontractor Management.

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

- **1. Pidilite Industries Ltd., Mahad-Raigad, Maharashtra, India.**Trainee / Apprentice Engineer (From 11th September 2012 to 10th September 2013)
- **2. Johnson Controls (India) Pvt. Ltd. (IEC-CoEE), Pune, Maharashtra, India.** Engineering Associate II (From 14th October 2013 to 12th April 2018)
- **3. Honeywell Automation India Ltd. (HBS-GES), Pune, Maharashtra, India.** System Engineer I (From 30th April 2018 to 30th September 2020)
- **4.** Honeywell International (India) Pvt. Ltd. (HBS-P&E), Pune, Maharashtra, India. Estimator II (From 1st October 2020 to Till Date)

EDUCATIONAL BACKGROUND

- Bachelor of Engineering: Instrumentation & Controls Engineering
- University: Pune University, Maharashtra, India.
- College: D.Y. Patil Institute of Engineering & Technology, Pimpri, Pune-18, MH, India
- Year of Graduation (Class): 2012 (First Class with Distinction)

PERSONAL INFORMATION

- Date of Birth: 26th Feb 1991
- Marital Status: Married
- Permanent Address: 210/B, Siddhivinayak Complex, Kakartale, Mahad, Dist.-Raigad, Maharashtra, India, Pincode-402301.